all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh... *
-*哦...*
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
所有：海绵宝宝！
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
* *
**
- I wanted to be
- 我想成为
mermaid man this year.
今年的美人鱼男。
- Trick or treat.
- 不给糖就捣蛋。
I love Halloween.
我喜欢万圣节。
Whoa!
哇！
- Ah!
- 啊！
Hm...
嗯...
Mm-hm.
嗯嗯。
It's scary, but...
这很可怕，但是...
* *
**
Oh. Hello.
哦。你好。
[zapping, SpongeBob screams
and grunts]
[海绵宝宝尖叫声
和咕哝]
* *
**
Hm...
嗯...
- Hello!
- 你好！
- Hello, Sir Patrick.
- 你好，帕特里克爵士。
How do you like
my decorations?
你喜欢怎样
我的装饰品？
[horse neighs,
decorations twinkle]
[马嘶声，
装饰品闪烁]
- Those are too cute
- 那些太可爱了
for Halloween, SpongeBob.
万圣节，海绵宝宝。
- Oh, Patrick, Halloween
is cute.
- 哦，帕特里克，万圣节
很可爱。
Sharing candy, holding hands,
singing songs.
分享糖果，牵手，
唱歌。
It's a bright and cheery
time of year.
这是一个明亮而欢快的
一年中的某个时间。
- I thought it was about
- 我以为是关于
getting your pants scared off.
吓得你裤子都掉了
Hey, where's your costume?
嘿，你的服装在哪里？
Close your eyes.
闭上你的眼睛。
Okay. Open 'em.
好的。打开它们。
- * I'm a lovely flower *
- *我是一朵可爱的花*
Ooh...
哦...
- Oh, that's not scary
either, SpongeBob.
-哦，这并不可怕
要么，海绵宝宝。
Wait, I'll show you
what's scary is.
等一下，我给你看
可怕的是。
- Let's go to this house.
- 我们去这所房子吧。
Oh...
There is no candy here...
哦...
这里没有糖果...
- Only onions!
- 只有洋葱！
Now move along.
现在继续前进。
Ooh....
哦....
- No candy.
- 没有糖果。
That is so scary.
那太可怕了。
Right, SpongeBob?
对吧，海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob?
海绵宝宝？
SpongeBob, why are you hiding
in there?
海绵宝宝，你为什么躲起来
在那里？
You'll miss all the
scary stuff.
你会错过所有的
可怕的东西。
- I don't want to see
the scary stuff, Patrick.
- 我不想看到
可怕的事情，帕特里克。
Okay? I admit it.
好的？我承认。
I love trick-or-treating,
我喜欢“不给糖就捣蛋”
but I am too afraid
to go out on Halloween!
但我太害怕了
万圣节出去玩！
- SpongeBob, don't you know
the old saying?
- 海绵宝宝，你不知道吗
老话说？
"The only thing you have
to fear is..."
“你唯一拥有的东西
恐惧是……”
Yourself!
你自己！
Aah!
啊啊！
Stop staring at me like that!
No!
别再这样盯着我了！
不！
See? It's all in your head,
SpongeBob.
看？一切都在你的脑海里
海绵宝宝。
You just have to remember
one simple trick,
你只需要记住
一个简单的技巧，
and that is:
scary equals funny.
那就是：
可怕等于有趣。
- Scary equals funny.
- 可怕等于有趣。
Hm. Never looked at it
that way before.
嗯。从来没看过
以前也是这样。
Doink!
多因克！
All right. I'll go out.
好的。我出去一下。
[ghost squeaks,
SpongeBob screams]
[幽灵的尖叫声，
海绵宝宝尖叫]
- Here I am.
- 我在这里。
Just looking for cavities.
只是寻找蛀洞。
Nope. None here.
没有。这里没有。
Oh, let's go out
and get scared.
哦，我们出去吧
并感到害怕。
both: Whoo!
两人：哇！
- Sure you can handle this,
SpongeBob?
- 当然你能处理这个，
海绵宝宝？
- Oh, I'll be fine, Patrick.
Really.
- 哦，我会没事的，帕特里克。
真的。
But can we hold hands,
just in case you get scared?
但我们能牵手吗
以防万一你害怕？
- Deal.
- 交易。
both: Whoa...
两人：哇……
- Welcome to my lab,
- 欢迎来到我的实验室，
SpongeBob and Patrick.
海绵宝宝和帕特里克。
I am the evil
Dr. Franken-Cheeks.
我就是邪恶
弗兰肯-奇克斯博士。
- Oh, hi, Sandy.
-哦，嗨，桑迪。
I didn't recognize you.
我没认出你来。
- Uh, yeah, great costume.
- 呃，是的，很棒的服装。
- Oh, thanks, guys.
-哦，谢谢，伙计们。
Now, feast your fingers
现在，尽情享受手指吧
on my jars of horror!
在我的恐怖罐子上！
Stick your hand in the jar
将手伸进罐子里
and guess what's inside...
猜猜里面有什么...
If you dare!
如果你敢的话！
- Oy.
- 哦。
Ew. Oh.
呃。哦。
Ew, it feels like worm guts.
呃，感觉就像虫子的内脏。
- Wrong!
- 错误的！
It's just noodles.
这只是面条。
Oh, I'm savvy to this game,
Sandy.
哦，我对这个游戏很了解，
桑迪。
So these brains are probably
a slimy head of lettuce,
所以这些大脑可能是
粘糊糊的生菜头，
or maybe some boiled broccoli.
或者一些煮西兰花。
- Wrong! It's--
- 错误的！它是 -
Patrick?
Get out of there.
帕特里克？
离开那里。
- Don't stop, SpongeBob.
That's the spot.
- 别停下来，海绵宝宝。
就是那个地方。
Ah...
啊...
- Patrick, you really got me.
- 帕特里克，你真的抓住了我。
- Ew!
- 呃！
How impolite of me!
我真是太无礼了！
I forgot to introduce you
我忘记介绍你了
to my little friend!
给我的小朋友！
Oh....
哦....
That's the most realistic
fake monster I ever saw.
这才是最现实的
我见过的假怪物。
- Who are you
calling fake?
- 你是谁
还叫假的？
- Fee,
- 费用，
fie, fo, fum,
嗳、嗬、嗬、
I smell the fear
我闻到了恐惧的味道
of a scared SpongeBob!
害怕的海绵宝宝！
Whoa!
哇！
* *
**
- I love it!
- 我喜欢它！
Oh, thank you, Sandy.
That was so much fun.
噢，谢谢你，桑迪。
那真是太有趣了。
Patrick, you were right.
帕特里克，你是对的。
Scary equals funny.
可怕等于有趣。
all: Hooray!
全体：万岁！
- Come in and see the horrors
- 进来看看恐怖的事情
of the Chum Bucket.
密友桶的。
* *
**
Ha, ha, ha, ha! I'm Plankton!
哈哈哈哈！我是浮游生物！
Ha, ha, ha, I'm evil!
哈哈哈，我邪恶了！
- Scary.
- 可怕的。
- What are you two
laughing about?
-你们两个是什么
笑什么？
There's nothing funny
about the food abuse
没有什么好笑的
关于食物滥用
that goes on at
the Chum Bucket!
发生在
密友桶！
You should be terrified!
你应该感到害怕！
- Oh, sorry, Mr. Krabs,
- 哦，对不起，蟹老板，
but our new philosophy is
但我们的新理念是
"scary equals funny."
“可怕等于有趣。”
- Yeah, and funny
divided by two idiots
- 是的，而且很有趣
被两个白痴分开
equals stupid.
等于愚蠢。
- I don't get it.
When I was a kid,
- 我不明白。
当我还是个孩子的时候，
Halloween meant
24 continuous hours
万圣节的意思
24小时连续
of screaming your head off!
尖叫你的头！
These kids today...
今天这些孩子...
Come to the Chum Bucket,
来到密友桶，
and witness the horrors
of the Krusty Krab!
并见证恐怖事件
蟹堡王！
You may never eat
a Krabby Patty again!
你可能永远不会吃东西
又来了蟹肉饼！
- Ready for more funny,
Sir Clanks
- 准备好迎接更多有趣的事情，
叮当爵士
- I'm driving!
- 我在开车！
Charge!
收费！
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- Welcome
to the Chum Bucket.
- 欢迎
到密友桶。
I'm Karen the cat.
我是猫凯伦。
- Do the scary part.
- 做可怕的部分。
Ooh, scary!
哦，可怕！
That's nothing.
那没什么。
Behold!
看哪！
The horrors of the Krusty Krab.
蟹堡王的恐怖。
Look down.
瞧不起。
Oh.
- Ooh.
哦。
- 哦。
* *
**
No dawdling! Step right up!
不磨磨蹭蹭！直接站起来吧！
The evil Mr. Krabs
邪恶的蟹老板
and his band of jolly,
mindless fools
和他的欢乐乐队，
无心的傻瓜
stalk Bikini Bottom
by night
茎比基尼泳裤
到了晚上
for delicious victims
为了美味的受害者
then drag their
lifeless bodies
然后拖动他们的
无生命的尸体
back to the kitchen,
回到厨房，
and grind them
并磨碎它们
into grinders!
进入研磨机！
Oh, Plankton,
you are a panic.
哦，浮游生物，
你很恐慌。
You're eating it!
你正在吃它！
Krabby Patties are people!
蟹黄饼是人！
They're people patties!
他们是人肉饼！
You're eating people patties!
你这是在吃人肉饼啊！
Come on!
快点！
- Ah! Music to me ears.
- 啊！音乐传到我耳边。
Halloween night,
and everyone is
万圣节之夜，
每个人都是
getting their bloomers
scared off!
得到他们的灯笼裤
吓跑了！
This holiday is the worst!
这个假期最惨了！
Wait a moment.
稍等。
That kid isn't
screaming with fear.
那个孩子不是
恐惧地尖叫。
- Scare and release!
- 吓唬然后释放！
I love this job.
我喜欢这份工作。
Ugh.
啊。
Who dares to laugh
谁敢笑
at All Hallows' Eve?
在万圣节前夕？
I'm going to find out.
我要去找出答案。
* *
**
Gee, who would've thought
哎呀，谁能想到
I'd be laughing myself silly
tonight?
我会笑自己傻
今晚？
- You!
- 你！
You dare to laugh
你还敢笑
on Halloween?
在万圣节？
Aren't you afraid
of scary things?
你不害怕吗
可怕的事情？
- Well, I was,
until I found out that
- 嗯，我当时，
直到我发现
scary equals funny.
可怕等于有趣。
I love this guy!
我爱这个家伙！
- I don't get it.
- 我不明白。
How could anyone
怎么会有人
confuse scary with funny?
混淆恐怖和搞笑？
* *
**
Hm. No wonder
you're not scared.
嗯。难怪
你不害怕。
These decorations
are laughable!
这些装饰品
可笑！
I'm sorry, kid.
对不起，孩子。
I had no idea
how fright-deprived you were.
我不知道
你是多么缺乏恐惧啊。
Not to worry.
不用担心。
You're in bad hands!
你的手不好！
* *
**
I'll show you
something to scream about
我会告诉你
值得尖叫的事情
aboard me ship!
登上我的船！
* *
**
You interested?
你有兴趣吗？
- Does a bear fish
sleep in the kelp forest?
- 熊会钓鱼吗
睡在海带森林里？
- Where are we going,
SpongeBob?
- 我们要去哪里，
海绵宝宝？
- We are going to
comedy heaven, Patrick.
- 我们要去
喜剧天堂，帕特里克。
This is going to be
so funny!
这将是
太有趣了！
- This music doesn't
sound funny, SpongeBob.
- 这个音乐没有
听起来很有趣，海绵宝宝。
- Stop that clanking.
- 别再发出叮叮当当的声音了。
- Sorry.
- 对不起。
- Yar!
- 啊！
- Oh! Hey!
- 哦！嘿！
- All bilge rats on deck!
- 甲板上所有的舱底老鼠！
We have company,
我们有公司，
and we want to show them
a good time!
我们想向他们展示
好时光！
That tickled.
那个痒痒的。
- Hang on to your bloomers,
SpongeBob.
- 抓紧你的灯笼裤，
海绵宝宝。
It's going to be
a bumpy fright.
这将会是
颠簸的恐惧。
* *
**
- * When you hear
the lonesome ring *
- * 当你听到
孤独的戒指*
* Of chimes that bring
the spirits singing *
*带来的钟声
灵魂在歌唱*
* Soon your spine
is tingling *
* 很快你的脊椎
刺痛*
* And there's just one
thing to say, Ahh! *
* 而且只有一个
想说的话，啊！ *
* Eyeballs in the dark
dilating *
* 黑暗中的眼球
扩张*
* Now your heart
is palpitating *
* 现在你的心
心悸*
* And there's only
just one thought *
* 并且只有
只是一个想法*
* That you can convey *
*您可以传达*
* Terror all around you *
*恐怖就在你身边*
* You can't get away *
*你无法逃脱*
* We take pride
in making sure *
* 我们感到自豪
确保*
* You have a frightful stay *
* 你的住宿经历很糟糕*
* Join the wretched chorus *
*加入可怜的合唱团*
* In the nightmare play *
*在噩梦中*
* And remember it's
all you can scream *
*并记住它是
你可以尖叫*
* At the ghost café *
*在幽灵咖啡馆*
* *
**
- Oh...
- 哦...
- * Terror all around you *
- *你周围充满恐怖*
* And we've just begun *
*我们才刚刚开始*
* You'll be
a trembling helpless *
*你会的
颤抖的无助*
* lump of fear
when we are done *
* 恐惧感
当我们完成时 *
* Grim unearthly creatures
flaunting *
* 可怕的超凡生物
炫耀*
* Nauseating features
make for *
* 令人作呕的功能
为*做
* Ghastly midnight
screechers *
* 可怕的午夜
尖啸者*
* You'll be speechless
but for Ahh! *
*你会无言以对
但对于啊！ *
* Surrender to the
horrifying *
* 屈服于
可怕*
* Phantom freaks whose
death-defying *
* 幻影怪胎
藐视死亡*
* Stunts of fearful madness
startle *
*可怕的疯狂特技
惊吓*
* With a shocking
interjection *
* 带着震撼
感叹词 *
* From which there is
no protection *
* 从其中有
无保护*
Boo!
嘘！
- Grr...
- 呃...
How can he still be laughing?
他怎么还能笑？
I've never been so humiliated.
我从来没有受过如此羞辱。
I got to do something here.
我必须在这里做点什么。
- Boy, Patrick,
I wish all our friends
- 男孩，帕特里克，
祝愿我们所有的朋友
could be here.
They'd love this place!
可能在这里。
他们一定会喜欢这个地方！
- Friends! He's got friends.
- 朋友们！他有朋友。
That's it!
I know how to scare this guy.
就是这样！
我知道怎么吓唬这个家伙。
* *
**
- Happy Halloween!
- 万圣节快乐！
W Where?
哪里？
- Trick or treat!
- 不给糖就捣蛋！
Oh!
哦！
- Hey!
- 嘿！
- SpongeBob!
- 海绵宝宝！
Patrick!
帕特里克！
Help me!
帮我！
That almost
looks like Sandy.
那差不多
看起来像桑迪。
- SpongeBob!
- Patrick.
- 海绵宝宝！
- 帕特里克.
- Help us!
- 帮助我们！
That almost
looked like
那差不多
看起来像
Mr. Krabs and Squidward
蟹老板和章鱼哥
and Gary and Plankton.
以及加里和浮游生物。
Funny.
有趣的。
Oh, Patrick,
this is hysterical.
哦，帕特里克，
这太歇斯底里了。
Why aren't you laughing?
你为什么不笑？
Patrick?
What's wrong with you?
帕特里克？
你这人怎么回事？
- Help me, SpongeBob.
- 帮帮我，海绵宝宝。
My body's butt itches!
我的身体屁股痒痒的！
Is this really happening?
这真的发生了吗？
Hey, this isn't funny.
嘿，这不好笑。
- I was wrong, SpongeBob.
- 我错了，海绵宝宝。
Sometimes, scary
equals scary.
有时候，很可怕
等于可怕。
Hm?
嗯？
- Yup. I got the same answer.
- 是的。我得到了同样的答案。
Scary equals "Ahh!"
可怕等于“啊！”
- Success!
- 成功！
I knew that would get him!
我知道那会得到他的！
Ah!!
啊！！
That's the scariest thing
I ever saw in my life!
这才是最可怕的
我这辈子见过！
- Me too. But we gotta go back.
- 我也是。但我们得回去了。
Are you nuts?
你疯了吗？
- Show a little backbone.
- 表现出一点骨气。
We gotta save our friends.
我们必须拯救我们的朋友。
- Oh, you're right.
But I'm still scared.
- 哦，你说得对。
但我还是很害怕。
Will you hold my hand?
你会握住我的手吗？
- Deal.
- 交易。
* *
**
- You know, I gotta say,
- 你知道，我得说，
pretty impressed with your
whole evil presentation here.
对你印象深刻
整个邪恶的演示都在这里。
Nice work.
干得好。
I could use a guy like you
to walk through walls.
我可以使用像你这样的人
穿过墙壁。
We take over the world,
and we split it, 70-30.
我们接管世界，
我们以 70-30 平分。
How's that grabbin' you?
这对你来说怎么样？
* *
**
Yes, master...
是的，主人...
- I guess with friends
like SpongeBob,
- 我想是和朋友一起
像海绵宝宝一样，
you don't need anemones,
huh, gang?
你不需要海葵
哈，帮派？
- You can't talk
about SpongeBob like that!
- 你不能说话
关于海绵宝宝就是这样！
If SpongeBob's
so great,
如果海绵宝宝
太棒了，
where is he
他在哪里
- And, now, I'm going to
roast your souls
- 现在我要
烤你的灵魂
over a devil pit.
越过恶魔深渊。
* *
**
Just like Grandma used to.
就像奶奶以前那样。
- Fire is so hot!
- 火太热了！
* *
**
You let my friends go,
你让我的朋友走，
buddy boy!
伙计男孩！
- You were trying to scare
me?
- 你是想吓唬人
我？
Now that is funny.
现在这很有趣。
You couldn't frighten me
你吓不到我
in a million eternities, kid.
一百万个永恒里，孩子。
- I think he could, master.
- 我想他可以，主人。
You've never seen
what's inside his brain!
你从未见过
他脑子里装的是什么！
Ha!
What's scary about that?
哈!
这有什么可怕的？
- I was in there once.
- 我去过那里一次。
It's too terrifying,
even for ghosts!
这也太可怕了吧
即使是鬼魂！
* *
**
- I'll decide if it's scary
or not!
- 我会决定是否可怕
或不！
* *
**
- Wa... Whoa!
- 哇...哇！
* *
**
- Ah! Ah! Ah! Don't--don't!
- 啊！啊!啊!别——别！
That didn't scare me
one bit.
这并没有吓到我
一点点。
I--I bet you don't
have a scary thought
我——我打赌你不会
有一个可怕的想法
in your entire brain!
在你的整个大脑中！
- Oh, scary... Hm...
- 哦，可怕...嗯...
You know, what always
scares me out of the room
你知道，什么总是
把我吓出了房间
is when my mom takes out
my naked baby pictures.
当我妈妈拿出来的时候
我的裸体婴儿照片。
I wuv you this much!
我太想你了！
I'm actually scared!
其实我很害怕！
So much horror!
太恐怖了！
* *
**
all: Ahh!
全体：啊！
- Ooh.
- 哦。
Oh.
哦。
- Oh! I got my butt back!
- 哦！我的屁股回来了！
- I don't know what's inside
that brain of yours,
- 我不知道里面有什么
你的大脑，
but I sure hope I never see it.
但我确实希望我永远不会看到它。
Thanks, SpongeBob.
谢谢，海绵宝宝。
- Sure. We learned
not to be afraid
- 当然。我们学到了
不要害怕
to never be scared
of being afraid again.
永远不要害怕
再次感到害怕。
- My employee saved us!
- 我的员工救了我们！
Party at the Krusty Krab!
在蟹堡王举办派对！
For a reasonable fee.
以合理的费用。
- Ugh.
- 呃。
What happened?
发生了什么？
Whew. Must have been
a nightmare.
呼。一定是
一场噩梦。
- Hey, guys!
- 嘿，伙计们！
Free candy!
免费糖果！
* *
**